<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>

<help_file>

<Language>English,English</Language>
<PluginContents>Named Folders</PluginContents>

<section title="Contents">
<title>Plugin for FAR "Named Folders".</title>
<title>Version <external name="ENG/VERSION"/>, <external name="ENG/DATE"/> </title>
<title><external name="ENG/COPYRIGHT"/> </title>.
  Program-Plugin #Named Folders# for #Far#.

  #Named Folders# is a tool for fast jumping to 
<link section="NamedFolderPaths">net, local or emulated folders</link>. You
can give short name for any folder then use this name to open this
folder in the active Far panel.
  You can use command "cd: soft" to fast launch programs from Start Menu.

  This plugin can be used through 
<link section="HowUseComandLine">command line</link> or 
<link section="HowUsePanel">virtual panel</link>.

  Don't hesitate to send me, 
<link section="Author">author</link> of this plugin, 
your suggestions, comments and questions.

  I want to express my thanks to Eugene Roshal and Far Group - for FAR. 
Brilliant program!

  <link section="Patterns">Command patterns</link> - short notations for frequently used commands.

  <link section="Settings">Settings</link> - settings of the plugin.
                            
  <link section="Reg">reg-files</link>  - description of registry files.

</section>

<section title="NamedFolderPaths">
<title>Named folders paths</title>
  You can specify named folder explicitly (local path, network path) or implicitly
(local path with metacharacters, environment variable, registry key). Implicit form
forces the plugin to search proper directories and to show to user all appropriated 
variants through <link section="MenuSelect">menu of variants</link>.

<ss>Variants of named folders paths</ss>
  #Local path# - path to local folders should be specified as "c:\path1\path2".
  #Network paths# - "\\Computer\path1\path2".
  #Environment variable# - "%path%".  In the case of such path, the plugin will show all
exists directories, specified in the environment variable with name "path" (through semicolons).
  #Registy key# - "$HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\\Software...".  Such path will force the plugin to find all
variables in the specified registry key and show to user all exists paths specified in these variables.
See <link section="Reg">sample</link>.

<ss>Metacharacters in local paths</ss>
It's possible to use metacharacters in local paths. Plugin supports a set of metacharacters. First of all, it supports standard FAR metacharacters:
 #*# - 0 or more characters.
 #?# - any character.
 #[a-z]# - any character from the set.
Secondly, it supports special metacharacters to limitate deep of search:
 #\**# - search deep in all nested directories without any limitations on search deep.
 #\..*# - search up in all parent directories without any limitations on search deep.
 #\**:N# - search deep on N levels. There is shot
syntax for the command: instead of #cd:pf\**:3# you can write #cd:pf\\\#. This possibility
works if and only if flag "Short syntax in paths" is turned on in plugin settings. Otherwise,
several slashes are handled as exactly single slash.                                                    
 #\..*:N# - search up on N levels. Short syntax of the command is #\....# (N + 1 dots).
If short syntax is turned off then N dots are interpreted as 2 dots (N > 2). Single dot is interpreted as single dot.
 #..# - The command #cd:pf..# is equal to #cd:pf\..# if short syntax is turned on.

 Possibility to regulate search deep is necessary to accelerate search. I.e. command "cd:pf\**\a" will search all directories in Program Files.
Usually, it will take a lot of time. But if you remember, that required directory is nested on 1-2 levels in Program files, you can execute
#cd:pf\**:2a" and take same results much(!) faster.

 If you execute search without search level limitations, you can stop it by pressing Esc and view already found directories.

<ss>Where you can use metacharacters</ss>
In third places:
 1. In command #cd:alias\path# - the plugin will open "based" directory (corresponded to "alias") and then open directory related to based one according to "path"-instructions.
 2. In the path that is linked by alias. F.e. you can create alias pf and specify directiron #c:\program files\**:4# for it.
 3. In commands of direct search when you specify directory path instead of alias name. I.e. you can type: #cd:c:\program files# or  #cd:"c:\program files\**:4\a"# and etc.

Plugin automatically transforms names to mask accoring to settings, see "Aliases mask expand mode" <link section="Settings">Settings</link>. But this
mode is used in above variants 1 and 3. If you specify path for alias using metacharacters, then you should specify all required metacharacters yourself.
</section>

 
<section title="HowUseComandLine">
<title>How use plugin through command line</title>

<ss>General commands syntax</ss>
  In the general case the command of plugin is writting as
  #cd:[command][catalog/][name][\path]# 

  #[catalog/]# - virtual catalog of the plugin;
  #[name]# - shortcut of named folder;
  #[\path]# - path related from the named folder.

  In the most cases, it's possible to use #*# and #?# in this names.

<ss>Opening shortcut</ss>
  #cd:name# - open on the active FAR panel the named folder for shortcut #name#. 
  #cd:catalog/name# - the same, but the plugin will search #name# in the catalog #catalog# 
and its subcatalogs only.
  #cd:name\path# - after opening #name# open related path #path#.
  #cd:~~text# - find all shortcuts which named folders paths contain #text#.
	#cd:%var%# - open directory corresponded to environment variable #var#; 
if there are several directories in this directory (";"), the plugin allows
to selecte required directory through variant selection menu. No exist
directories are excluded from search results.
 #cd:%var# - command same as previous. There are a couple of differences. 
This command allows to specify part of environment variable name, not a 
whole name. So, you can use #cd:%p# instead of #cd:%path%# and 
#cd:%e# instead of #cd:%temp%#. Important issue: this command searchs
mask *var* not only in the environment variable names, but in paths too.
So, if results of command "cd:%c" will include "windir - c:\windows" because
path "c:\windows" matches to mask "*c*".
  #cd:path# - open specified path. Path must be absolute local path and may contains 
metacharacters. You can use ".RelativePath" to search "RelativePath" relatively 
current directory. "path" can be network directory, i.e. "cd:\\computer_name"

<ss>Search files</ss>
  #cd:--f sh\path# - search all files matched "path" in named folder corresponded to alias "sh". Open directory which
contains selected file.
  #cd:--df sh\path# - search all files and subdirectories matched "path" in named folder corresponded to alias "sh". 
Open selected subdirectory or subdirectory which contains selected file.
  The distributive of the plugin contains files "cdf.reg" and "cf.reg" to set command patterns for
these commands.
  Commands #cd:--f# and #cd:--df# allow to specify path directly, without using alias. 
F.e. #cd:--f c:\temp#, #cd:--df \\computer\abc#, etc. If path contains spaces, it's necessary to quote it, f.e.:
#cd: "c:\program files\**:3\*b"#.


<ss>Creation of catalogs and shortcuts</ss>
  #cd::name# - create constant shortcut in the root catalog;
  #cd::catalog/name# - create constant shortcut in the #catalog#;
  #cd:+name# - create temporary shortcut (it will be deleted automatically after rebooting - this feature doens't work in NF 4.X);
  #cd:::name# - create single shortcut for two directories (opened on active and inactive FAR panels);
  #cd::+name# - the same, but shortcut will be temporary;
  #cd::#, #cd:::#, #cd:+#, #cd::+# - create shortcut with the name equal to the name of currently opened directory.
  #cd::catalog/# - create catalog.

<ss>Deleting catalogs and shortcuts</ss>
  #cd:-name# - delete shortcut;
  #cd:-catalog/name# - delete shortcut from specified catalog;
  #cd:-# - delete shortcut for currently opened directory or its subdirectories;
  #cd:-catalog/# - delete catalog.

<ss>Opening of the plugin panel</ss>
  #cd:# - open virtual panel;
  #cd:catalog/# - open virtual panel and jump to the specified catalog; 

<ss>Execute program from #Start# menu</ss>
	See <link section="StartApplication">Execute applications</link>.

<ss>Additional method to execute plugin command</ss>
  It's possible to execute any command through "Command execution dialog".
</section>

<section title="StartApplications">
<title>Execute applications</title>
  #cd: soft# - search shortcuts in Start Menu with names matched to "*soft*" and show list of them.
Press Enter to execute program, Ctrl+Alt+Enter to open program's path in Far, Ctrl+Enter to open
program's path in Explorer. It's possible to set in the 
<link section="Settings">settings</link> dialog list of masks for shortcuts that should be skipped.
You can use parameters: #cd: soft params#

<ss>Command keys in variants menu</ss>
 #F11# - display/hide applications, that are matched to ignore masks, 
specified in <link section="Settings">settings</link>.
 #Enter# - execute selected application.
 #Ctrl + Enter# - open application directory in Explorer.
 #Ctrl + Altr + Enter# - open application directory in FAR.
 #Shift + Enter# - execute selected application in background without closing the menu.
 #Ctrl + Shift + Enter# - open application directory in Explorer without closing the menu.
 #F2# - show application names only.
 #F3# - show catalogs and application names.
</section>

<section title="Settings">
<title>Settings</title>
  #Always show all variants# - if this flag is on, then the plugin shows list of all available variants  
even if exact match is available (last one will be on the top of the list).  Otherwise, the
plugin automatically selects exact match.


<ss>Confirmations</ss>
	#Delete# - confirm deletion of any shortcut/catalog.

	#Always show all variants# - show menu of variants always, event if only single variant was found.
	#Open \\ as net:\\# - open network paths through Network plugin (it can be useful in the case 
of password protected directories).
	#Aliases mask expand mode# - specify how to expand masks in the local paths.
  0 - a -> *a*
  1 - a -> a*
  2 - a -> a
  For example, "cd:x\a\b*\c":
	0 - *a*\b*\*c*
  1 - a*\b*\c*
  2 - a\b*\c

	#Use single menu mode# - specify the behavior of the "cd:a\b" commands. If this flag is set off, 
the plugin shows two menus: first for aliases "a*' and second for paths, 
available for the alias, selected by the user in the first menu. 
If this flag is set on, the plugin shows single menu with all paths 
available for all aliases. 

	#Subdirectories as aliases# - "cd:a" will search "a" in the list of aliases and in the list of subdirectories of
the current directory. All subdirectories are displayed in the list of aliases as ".\abc"

	#Panel mode# - Panel of Named Folder in the mode Ctrl+8 uses non-standart settings of the panel - 
to show additional column with the states of directories. So, you can't set withds of columns for
this mode through standart FAR-dialog. This option allows to do it. Width settings is written in the 
form "Types of columns";"With of columns". By default: "N,Z,C0;10,0,5". 
Please see for detailes <link section=":PanelViewModes">the documentation of the FAR.</link>.
	

</section>


<section title="HowUsePanel">
<title>How use virtual file panel "Named folders"</title>
  You can open this panel through the #Change disk menu#, #Plugins command# menu or by using the command "cd:".

  It's possible to use next keys.
  #Shift+F4# - create new shortcut; See <link section="NamedFolderPaths">paths</link> for possible named folders values.
  #F4# - modify shortcuts properties;
  #F5# - copy selected shortcuts or/and catalogs;
  #F6# - move selected shortcuts or/and catalogs;
  #F7# - create catalog. 
  #F8# - delete selected shortcuts or/and catalogs;
  #Enter# - open selected named folder;
  #Shift+Enter# - open selected named folder in the Windows Explorer;
  #Ctrl+Enter# - open selected named folder in the inactive FAR panel.
  #Ctrl+R# - refresh panel.
  #Ctrl+PgUp# - go to the parent catalog.

  Also it's possible to copy any directory to the plugins panel - shortcut for this 
directory will be created implicitly.
</section>

<section title="DialogExecuteCommand">
$^#Execution Command Dialog
  Execution command dialog is alternative for command line.
You can use it to execute <link section="HowUseComandLine">same command as in the command line</link>. 
In comparison with command line this dialog give additional possibilities:
  - it's not necessary to type prefix #cd:#; 
  - this dialog supports the commands history (you can switch it on/of in the <link section="Settings">settings</link>)
  - through dialog you can execute any plugin command at any time. 
(you can't use #cd:# in command line (beginning at Far 1.70b5) if any virtual panel is opened). 
	
  To quick opening #Execution command dialog# use #Ctrl+D# (you should execute #ApplyCommand.reg# to 
switch on this possibility).
</section>

<section title="MenuSelect">
<title>Variants menu</title>	
 #Variants menu# allows users to select required shortcut from the list, when 
plugin find several shortcuts matched to users command. 

  In this menu you can use several keys.

  Use #Enter# to choose selected shortcut.
  Use #Del# to delete selected shortcut.
	Use #F4# to edit selected shortcut.
	
  Use #F5#-#F9# to change display mode.
  #F5# - display shortcuts only;
  #F6# - display values of shortcuts only;
  #F7# - display shortcuts and their catalogs;
  #F8# - display all: catalogs, shortcuts and their values.
  #F9# - display shortcuts and values;

  Use #Ctrl+F5#, #Ctrl+F6#, #Ctrl+F7# to sort results by columns 1, 2, 3. 
Use #Ctrl+F12# to turn off sorting of results.	

  Use #F11# - to switch showing catalogs mode (between normal mode
and pseudo-treelike one).

  The plugin remembers selected mode.

	You can filter variants in menu. F.e. try to type "abc cde". Then
menu will show only paths which contains "abc" AND "cde". 
</section>

<section title="DialogEditCatalog">
<title>Catalog creation</title>
Specify name of new catalog as "abc" or "abc/cde". Absolute name is
started from "/".
</section>

<section title="DialogEditShortcut">
<title>Edit shortcut</title>
  #Catalog# - catalog where shortcut will be placed. 
  #Shortcut# - name of created shortcut.
  #Directory for active panel#  - directory to be opened on active FAR panel after shortcut execution.
This directory can be local, network or directory on the another plugin. It can contain metacharaters, see section <link section="NamedFolderPaths">Named Folder Paths</link> for details.
  #Directory for inactive panel#- directory to be opened on inactive FAR panel after shortcut execution (optional parameter)
  #Temporary# - this shortcut will be removed after computer restart (this feature doesn't work in NF 4.X, so temporary shortcuts are equal to general shortcuts).
</section>

<section title="DialogMove">
<title>Copy/move catalogs and shortcuts</title>
Catalogs and shortcuts can be copied/moved from panel to panel (if you open two NF-panels in FAR).
You can copy/move them using single panel only by edit their paths in appropriate way. New paths can be 
specified as absolute or relative paths. Absolute path is started from "/".

There is an example. Assume, that original catalog structure is:
 /1
 /1/2
 /1/3

Open catalog "/1" and command to rename catalog "2". Enter new path for "2":
New path "/2". Result is:
 /1
 /1/3
 /2

New path "4". Result is:
 /1
 /1/4
 /1/3

New path "3". Result is:
 /1
 /1/3/2

Ïóòü "..". Ðåçóëüòàò:
 /1
 /1/3
 /2

and so on.
</section>

<section title="DialogPatterns">
<title>Edit command patterns</title>

see <link section="Patterns">Command patterns</link>. 

<ss>Commands in the patterns menu</ss>
#F4# - edit selecte pattern.
#Ins# - insert new pattern.
#Del# - delete pattern.
#Esc# - exit menu.

</section>

<section title="Patterns">
<title>Patterns of the commands</title>
  Patterns allow us to short notations for frequently used commands. Separated prefix is assigned to each pattern.
When user execute pattern command, the plugin modify text of the command as consistent with the pattern and 
then execute this modified command.

<ss>Example of pattern</ss>
  Let's create pattern for command "cd: :soft". We want to make this command more short - "cs:soft".
Create such pattern:
  Prefix: "cs:"
  Pattern: "[command]= ;[name]=:[name]"
  The plugin will modify any command, executed through "cs:" in accordance with two rules:
  1) #[command]= #. The command must be always " ".
  2) #[name]=:[name]# The colon must be added before name of shortcut.
  So in accord to this pattern all commands like "cs:soft", "cs:+soft", "cs:~~soft" will be 
translated to "cs: :soft".
  Tags #command# and #name# in the left parts of equalities are refereed to the parts of the result command.
Tags in the right parts are refereed to the parts of original command.

<ss>Parts of command</ss>
  In the general case, any command of the plugin can be written as:
  #[Prefix][Command][Catalog][CDelim][Name][PDelim][Path][Params]#
where:  
  #Prefix# - prefix, f.e. "cd:"
  #Command# - command (f.e. ":", "::", "--f",  etc)
  #Catalog# - catalog (f.e., "catalog")
  #CDelim# - delimiter between catalog and shortcut (always "/");
  #Name# - name of shortcut (or name of the program in the command "cd: soft")
  #PDelim# - delimiter between shortcut and local path (usually "\", but it can be equal to "\\", ".", "\*\" ¨ etc)
  #Path# - local path (path related named folder)
  #Params# - parameters of the command.
  You can assign in the pattern only one transformation rule to any part of the command. If transformation rule is not
specified, the part of the command will not be modified.

<ss>Additional examples.</ss>
#Direct access to the shortcut#. You can assign prefix to direct access to named folder. 
Then you can use names of subdirectories of this named folder as shortcuts. 
 Prefix: ShortuctName
 Command: [name]=[prefix]\[name]*
Example: Create shortcut "zp" for directory "z:\projects", then use "zp:prj1", "zp:prj2" to jump to the directory of
concrete project.

#Direct access to catalog#. You can omit name of catalog - it will be automatically substituted to all commands.
 Prefix: CatalogName
 Command: [catalog]=CatalogName

#Search files#. New command --f demonstrates syntax of all future commands of the plugin: --CommandName.
This is not short commands, so you can use patterns to create short notation for them.
 Prefix: cf
 Command: [command]=--f
See reg file: "cf.reg"

#Remove restrictions for search level#. 
 Prefix: cg
 Command: [pdelim]=\*\
Example: cg:.\b - search "b" in ALL subfolders of the current directory.

#Separated prefix for "cd: soft". Always store current path in the clipboard.
 Prefix: cs
 Command: [command]= ;[name]=:[name]
See reg file: "cs.reg"

#Search in the current directory#. 
  Prefix: cc
  Command: [command]=--df ;[name]=.;[path]=[name]
Examples:
  cc:abc\** -> cc:.\**abc
See reg file: "cc.reg"

</section>


<section title="Author">
<title>Far Named Folders - the plugin for Far Manager.</title>
  <external name="ENG/COPYRIGHT"/>

  This program is FREEWARE.
   
  The author is not responsible for any consequences of using
this product, though in testing he didn't find anything terrible in it.

  Author: <external name="ENG/AUTHOR"/>
  Russia, Krasnoyarsk.
  E-Mail: #<external name="CONTACT_EMAIL_HELP"/>#
  #<external name="RAMMUS_WWW"/>#
</section>

<section title="Reg">
<title>Content of reg-files</title>

 #FastPrefix.reg#: set #:# to "cd:".

 #ApplyCommand.reg#: set hot key #Ctrl+D# for "Command execution dialog"

 #StdPaths.reg#: create two shortcuts "stda" ¨ "stdu" for system folders
(for all users and current user correspondingly). This is an example of using Registry Key as the value of named folders.

 #SoftIgnoreMasks.reg#  create in the registry list of mask for shortcuts, tha should be ignored 
by "cd: soft" (*readme* and *uninstall*).
 
 #Subfolder Patterns# - several convenient <link section="Patterns">command patterns.</link>
</section>
</help_file>