<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>

<whatsnew>
<version product_name="Named Folders" version="3.0.0.243" date="snapshot"> 
<group title="Key changes">
<item type="!">Plugin uses Far API 2.0 and unicode.</item>	
<item type="!">64-bit version of the plugin is released. Now plugin is available both for x86 and x64.</item>	
<item type="!">Plugin has own open source project on google code: 
http://code.google.com/p/namedfolders/. You can write bugreports and suggestion to
issue tracker here. You can also download most recent snapshot of the plugin
(all releases will be send to PlugRing as previously).</item>	
<item type="!">NF3 doesn't work correctly with russian shortcuts, that
were created on NF2. As result, it's necessary to recreate all shortcuts,
that contain Russian letters in names and in paths.</item>
</group>
<group title="Changes">
<item type="-">Launch of x64-apps from FAR x86 is fixed, see #6 
(http://code.google.com/p/namedfolders/issues/detail?id=6)</item>	
<item type="*">Procedure of removing douple prefixes is changed. In previous
versions NF, command "cD:ab:command" was equal to "cd:command" and  
command "cd:cd:cd:command" didn't work at all. Now, the plugin ignores
all prefixes except last one. So, the command "ab:cd:ef:command" is
equal to "ef:command".</item>
<item type="*">Search in local paths is changed. No, the command "cd:alias.." 
can be written in more classic way "cd:alias\..". Both variants ".." and "\.."
are supported to specify parent folder.</item>
<item type="+">New possibility to edit shortuct from variants menu.
F4 is used to edit menu. To change view mode "shorctuts and values" on
plese use F7 instead of F4.</item>
</group>
</version>

<version product_name="Named Folders" version="2.5.2 пострелиз" date="Unpublished">
<item type="*">If flag "subdirectories as aliases" is turned on, then 
plugin searches subfolders using mask "a*" (not "*a*" as previously).</item>
<item type="*">If you copy directory on the plugin panel, dialog of alias
creation appears. So, you are able to edit name of alias. In previous versions
of the plugin, there was no possibility to make the edition.</item>
<item type="-">Mode "Show all variants" didn't work.</item>
<item type="!">Now ".." is used in local paths to specify "jump on one level above" 
(instead of "."). It allows to use char "." in masks, i.e. "cd:f\*.exe"</item>
<item type="-">Search with local path can lead to path duplicates in list of 
path variants.</item>
<item type="-">Shortcuts with characters "#", "@", "(", ")" in name didn't work.</item>
<item type="*">Rename of "/@@" to "##" using Shift+F6 leaded to incorrect 
creation of catalog "##".</item>
<item type="-">Plugin used fixed width of panel columns instead of taking
width from settings.</item>
</version>

<version product_name="Named Folders" version="2.5.1 postrelease" date="13.01.2006">
<item type="-">Named folders with backslashes didn't work.</item>
<item type="-">Fixed an error of the compilation - previous version of the
plugin demands msvcp71.dll</item>
<item type="-">The plugin uses fixed width (8,0) of columns on the panel instead of
taking default values for widths</item>
</version>

<version product_name="Named Folders" version="2.5 release" date="9.01.2006">
<item type="+">Add filter to all menus of variants. If you type "abc cde" in the
menu, then menu will show only variants that contain "abc" AND "cde" in the
path or name of alias. For typing local characters (i.e. russian) press SHIFT.</item>
<item type="+">New configuration parameter "Use single menu mode". 
It specify the behavior of the "cd:a\b" commands. If this flag is set off, 
the plugin shows two menus: first for aliases "a*' and second for paths, 
available for the alias, selected by the user in the first menu. 
If this flag is set on, the plugin shows single menu with all paths 
available for all aliases.</item>
<item type="-">Fixed bug with opening paths which contain russian letters.</item>
<item type="-">Fixed bug in the command "cd: :soft" - russian letters in
the path were stored in the clipboard in the wrong encoding.</item>
<item type="-">It was not possible to set plugin's hotkey for the disk menu.</item>
<item type="-">Buttons Ok and Cancel didn't work in the dialogs in new FAR (alpha 6).</item>
<item type="-">Fixed bug with opening local paths that contain metacharacters</item>
<item type="-">Fixed bug with appearing of double-slashes near the disk letter 
after coping directory to the plugins panel.</item>
<item type="-">The plugin hangs on opening "net:\\abc" from the plugins panel
in the new versions of FAR (alpha 6, build 2060).</item>
<item type="+">New configuration parameter "Aliases mask expand mode". 
You can specify how to expand masks in the local paths. There are three possible
variants: 0: a -> *a*. 1: a -> a*; 2: a -> a.  For example, for "cd:x\a\*b\c": 
0 - *a*\b*\*c*,  1 - a*\b*\c*,  2 - a\b*\c. Names a, b, c, which contain metacharacters,
are not transformed.</item>
<item type="+">There are two modes of the view in the variants menu of "cd: soft" now: 
with and without group name.</item>
<item type="*">New macros "FastPrefix.reg" replaced "FastPanel.reg". 
New macros assign ":" as a hotkey to call the plugin's panel. It automatically 
switches current keyboard layout to the english one (FAR 1.7 alpha 6 is required)</item>
<item type="*">Tree-like mode of catalog's showing was removed.</item>
<item type="*">A state of named folders is checked in the Ctrl+8 panel mode only. 
So all other modes (i.e Ctrl+6) work faster now.</item>
<item type="+">New configuration parameter "Subdirectories as aliases". 
When this mode is switched on, the command "cd:a" will search "a" in the list of aliases 
and in the list of subdirectories of the current directory. All subdirectories are
displayed in the list of aliases as ".\abc".</item>
<item type="*">Search files command (cf) was improved - the cursor of the FAR
panel is set on the selected file now.</item>
</version>


<version product_name="Named Folders" version="2.4 beta" date="22.06.2005">
   <item type="+">Patterns for commands - general mechanism 
to create short notations for frequently used commands of the plugin.
See help for details.
</item>
<item type="-">Several bugs in the command cd:% were fixed</item>
<item type="-">Command "cd: soft param" didn't work correctly, if
the "param" was absolute path to the file.</item>
<item type="+">Now you can stop search of the local paths by 
pressing Esc.</item>
<item type="+">Now you can use two directions of the search in the
mask of local directory. "\" is used to search in subdirectories,
"." is used to search in parent directories. So you can use
such masks as "cd:a\\path", "cd:a..path", "cd:a.*\path", etc.
Note: "." is special symbol now, you should not use it in the names
of shortcuts.
</item>
<item type="+">Now it's possible to make global search of local path
(i.e. search without any restrictions of the nesting level).
"cd:sh\*\ab" - search "down"
"cd:sh.*.ab" - search "up"</item>
<item type="*">Hotkeys were added to the settings dialog.</item>
<item type="-">Fixed bugs with "Delete all" and "Skip".</item>
<item type="*">The confirmation of deletion is common for 
deletion of the shortcuts and empty catalogs. There is individual
confirmation for deletion of non-empty catalogs.</item>
<item type="*">The dialog of execution now is not closed
after unsuccessful execution of the command.</item>
<item type="-">Implicit commands were not work correctly
when the name of the catalog was specified (f.e, "cD::cat/")</item>
<item type="+">New form of the command "cd:path" - "cd:.relativepath" (with point) - 
search "relativepath" relatively current directory.</item>
<item type="+">New command "cd:--f sh\path" search files matched to "path"
in the named directory "sh".</item>
<item type="+">New command "cd:--df sh\path" search files and subdirectories
matched to "path" in the named directory "sh"</item>
<item type="+">New reg-files "cs.reg", "cf.reg", "cdf.reg","cc.reg" 
(see subdirectory Patterns) - patterns for commands 
"cd: :soft", "cd:--f ", "cd:--df ", "cd:.\"</item>

</version>

<version product_name="Named Folders" version="2.3.3 postrelease" date="4.04.2005">
<item type="-"> Fixed bug in "cd:sh\\\path" - path was searched only on the last 
level, not on all three required levels (the bug was appeared in the case of 
the path without metacharacters).</item>
<item type="+">New possibility to open shortcuts for network directories
through Network plugin. It's useful in the case of network paths protected 
by the password. This feature is switched off by default.</item>
<item type="*">Now the plugin "press" Ctrl+Y before open shortcut 
for virtual directory (to clear current command line content before
sending there keys sequence).</item>
<item type="+'">New feature for command "cd: soft". If you place colon
before soft "cd: :soft" then the plugin store path to current directory 
to the clipboard. It's useful, if you want to open an application and 
save then new file to directory, currently opened in the FAR. 
I.e. "cd: :word".</item>
<item type="+'">Now you can specify disk menu hotkey for Named Folders.</item>
<item type="+'">It's possible now to change the plugin's virtual panel 
view mode settings (only for default mode "Files owners", Ctrl+8). 
In the plugin's configuration set value for "panel mode" like this:
"N,Z,C0;10,0,5" (columns through commas, semicolon, widths for columns).</item>
</version>


<version product_name="Named Folders" version="2.3.2 postrelease" date="21.03.2005">
<group title="Functionality">
<item type="+">Now it's possible to execute "cd: soft" with parameters.
Selected application will be executed with these parameters.
Example: "cd: word abc.txt" (to open file "abc.txt" in MsWord)"</item>
<item type="!">Now minimum system requirements for Named Folders are
Win9X/WinNT + IE4.0. The plugin was tested under Win98SE.</item>
<item type="+">New command "cd:path". "Path" must be absolute
local path. So, you can use local drive's letters as shortcuts.
Example: "cd:z:\\a*" </item>
<item type="+">New TODO page on the Names Folders's site: 
<a href="http://www.rammus.ru/?tag=nf_todo">http://www.rammus.ru/?tag=nf_todo</a></item>
<item type="+">Now it's possible to delete all selected shortcuts
without unnecessary confirmations (DeleteAll button was added). </item>
<item type="*">Now "cd:abc:sh" with two or more letters in abc is equivalent to "cd:sh".</item>
</group>
<group title="Fixed bugs">
<item type="-">Error with creation of the folders with russian names
was fixed.</item>
<item type="-">Names of folders with ampersands in the names
were not correctly displayed in the selection menu. Fixed.</item>
<item type="-">Masks with "[]" didn't work when they contain no more
metachars and "[]" contains two or more characters. Fixed.
Example: С:\Tasks\[TD]o[dn][oe]. </item>
<item type="-">Now "cd:path" is executed as "cd:*path*" if there are no metacharacters
in the path and as "cd:path*" otherwise. I.e. you can search now paths
by first letters in their names.</item>
<item type="-">Fixed several bugs with positioning cursor after
creation folders and refreshing.</item>
</group>
</version>


<version product_name="Named Folders" version="2.3.1 postrelease" date="16.08.2004">
<group title="Functionality">
<item type="+">Now you can set named folders path in the form
"%environment variable%\related path". E.g. "%windir%\system32".</item>
<item type="*">Now you can omit asterix after last slash in the
local path. I.e. "cd:pf\" is equal "cd:pf"</item>
</group>
<group title="Fast launching problems">
<item type="+">In the command "cd: soft" you can set now "soft" in the
form "group mask\shortcuts mask". E.g. "cd: adobe\*" will find
all shortcuts in all groups which names is matched to "*adobe*" </item>
<item type="-">Bug with ANSI/OEM characters in the list of 
ignored masks for "cd: soft" was fixed</item>
<item type="-">Switching between ignore-on/off modes in the variants menu 
leaded to closing of menu</item>
</group>
<group title="Virtual panel">
<item type="-">It wasn't possible to type R in the command line with 
opened plugins panel.</item>
<item type="-">Fixed several bugs with positioning cursor after
creation (Shift+F4) and copying/moving (F5/F6) of shortcuts.</item>
</group>
</version>


<version product_name="Named Folders" version="2.3 release" date="1.08.2004">

<group title="Fast launching programms">
<item type="+">New possibility to set in the configurations 
list of mask of shortcuts which should be ignored. </item>
<item type="+">New reg-file "SoftIgnoreMasks.reg" with 
several common masks which should be ignored (*Uninstall*, 
*readme* and *read me*)</item>
<item type="+">Two modes of variants menu: with hidden ignored 
shortcuts and with not hidden. In the last mode there is an 
asterix in the title of menu.</item>
<item type="-">Didn't work fast launching of Excel and Word</item>
<item type="+">Now function of fast launching should work under
all versions of Windows.  </item>
<item type="+">Now it's possible to open directory for selected
shortcut from variants menu. Use  Shift+Enter to open directory 
in Far and  Ctrl+Enter to open it in Explorer</item>
<item type="+">The paths of shortcuts now is displayed as short
as possible (equal path for all variants are not displayed)</item>
</group>

<group title="Misc">
<item type="-">Fixed bug with creation of catalogs.</item>
<item type="-">Fixed several bugs with converting between
OEM and ANSI.</item>
<item type="-">Fixed bug with copying directory to plugins panel
(the plugin losts slash between directory name and its path)</item>
<item type="+">Now an asterix in the title of variants
menu is displayed in tree-like mode.</item>
<item type="-">List of appropriated paths in variants menu now
is sorted</item>
<item type="-">Fixed an error with pressing of BACKSPACE on the virtual
panel</item>
</group>

<group title="Sources">
<item type="*">From this versions source codes of Named Folders will not
be included in distributive on PlugRing. You can get them if you want on the site 
of the plugin: http://www.rammus.ru</item>
<item type="+">Several XSLT and XML files for autogeneration
of help and readme files were included in source codes.</item>
</group>

</version>



<version product_name="Named Folders" version="2.3 beta 1" date="10.05.2004">
<group title="Fast launching programs">
<item type="+"> New command "cd: soft" (prefix, space, pattern) 
for launching programs from Start menu.
The plugin search all programs shortcuts with names matched to "*soft*"
(or to "soft" if "soft" is already mask), suggest a list of all matched
shortcuts to user and launch selected shortcut.</item>
<item type="!"> New command is experimental. Please send your comments and suggestions.</item>
</group>

<group title="Support of OEM and ANSI">
<item type="-"> Didn't work shortcuts with local chars in the names.</item>
<item type="-"> Shortcuts to the registry key didn't allow to jump to the folders
with local chars in the path.</item>
</group>

<group title="Misc">
<item type="-"> Didn't work jumping to the nearest directory.</item>
<item type="-"> Shortcuts for paths like "c:\", "d:\", etc didn't work.</item>
<item type="-"> The states of shortcuts with metacharacters in their paths were
incorrectly displayed as "Not found".</item>
<item type="-"> Now it's possible to freely use "/" instead of "\" in the paths of 
local named folders.</item>
</group>
</version>

<version product_name="Named Folders" version="2.2.1 postrelease" date="20.04.2004">
<item type="-"> Shortcuts to folders with symbols [] in the paths didn't work. </item>
<item type="-"> In the Far 1.7 alpha 6 if you opened not exist shortcut and specify 
any local path, the plugin show list of subfolders of the current folder.</item> 
<item type="+"> Now, you can directly specify the name of required registry value 
for shortcut to registry key. I.e. You can use "cd:stdu\co" to jump 
to "cookies".</item>
</version>

<version product_name="Named Folders" version="2.2 release" date="15.04.2004">

<group title="Support of metacharacters in paths">
<item type="+"> Now it's possible to set the depth of the searching in the paths of
local named folders and in the related paths. The depth of the searching
are regulated by the number of slashes. N slashes mean: "search folder 
among all folders with nesting level less or equal N. I.e.:
	"b\a"  - search "a" among subfolders of "b"
	"b\\a" - search "a" among subfolders of "b" and their subfolders.    
	etc.</item>
<item type="+"> Now it's possible to use FAR's metacharacters (?, * and [a-b, z]) in the 
named folders paths. Scope of "*" is NOT spreaded to the subfolders.
You should explicitly specify the depth of the searching by the number of 
slashes.</item>

<item type="!"> Useful examples:
   - Now you can specify single shortcut for all "Program Files" folders
     "pf" = "?:\Program Files" or "[c-d, f]:\Program Files".
   - There is new fast method to jump to the folder, located somewhere in
     the named folder:
     "cd:pf\office", "cd:pf\\vc", "cd:pf\\delphi", "cd:pf\\\atl" etc.</item>
</group>

<group title="Support of the system directories">
<item type="+"> Now you can specify the registry key as a path of named folder:
"$HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\\Software..." (first character must be "$").
For such named folder the plugin will look through the values of this key,
find all values, which contains paths to exists folders and 
will allow to user select one of these folders.</item>
<item type="!"> Such feature allows us to get access to all system folders
(like "My documents", "History", "Favorites" etc) through the single
shortcut.</item>
<item type="+"> New file  "StdPaths.reg" was added to Named Folders distributive.
This file create shortcuts "stda" and "stdu" for system folders
(for all users and current user correspondingly).</item>
</group>

<group title="Variants menu">
<item type="*"> Variants menu was improved. Now you can view catalogs
in two modes: standard and pseudo-treelike :). 
Switch them by F11.</item>
</group>

<group title="Misc">
<item type="*"> Method of opening shortcuts for two directories was improved.
Now the plugin always open first directory on the left panel, 
and the second one on the right panel. It doesn't matter which 
panel is currently active. If you open shortcut with pressed Ctrl, 
first directory will be opened on the right panel and so on.</item>
<item type="*"> Shift+Del delete catalogs and shortcuts. </item>
</group>
</version>

<version product_name="Named Folders" version="2.1.2 postrelease" date="4.04.2004">
<item type="-"> Now it's possible to use ":" as the prefix of the plugin.</item>
<item type="+"> Now you can save current view mode of the plugin's panel as default one 
by Shift+F9.</item>
<item type="*"> The command "cd:%var" was changed. Now, "var" will be located
not only in the names of environment variables, but also in their paths.
So, the command "cd:%32", for example, will show "c:\windows\system32" 
(from "path"). </item>
</version>

<version product_name="Named Folders" version="2.1.1 release" date="14.03.2004">
<item type="-"> The bug with "&amp;" now is removed completely. </item>
</version>

<version product_name="Named Folders" version="2.1 release" date="8.03.2004">
<group title="General">
<item type="+"> Now you can view state of local directories (exists, partly exists or
    not found) in the "File owners" (Ctrl+8) view mode. </item>
<item type="-"> The plugin didn't work correctly if the named folders with the "&amp;" in 
    the path was selected.  </item>
</group>
<group title="Variants menu">
<item type="+"> Menu was divided on the collumns.</item> 
<item type="+"> In the menu with environment variables it's possible now to view 
    variables names. </item>
</group>
</version>

<version product_name="Named Folders" version="2.0 release" date="24.02.2004">
<group title="Command line">
<item type="*"> Now display mode in the shortcuts menu is stored always. </item>
<item type="-"> The command "cd::+shortcut" worked incorrectly. </item>
<item type="-"> The command "cd::catalog/shortcut" didn't work. </item>
</group>
<group title="Configuration dialog">
<item type="-"> Tab order was corrected. </item>
<item type="-"> The option "hide temporary shortcuts" was returned. </item>
<item type="-"> Plugin's prefix wasn't saved. </item>
<item type="+"> New command: "cd:%var%" to open directory specified in the 
    environment variable "var"; if this variable contains 
    several paths (separated by ";"), the plugin allows to 
    select required path from the list. Incomplete syntax
    of command is supported: for example, you can  
    use "cd:%p" instead of "cd:%path%". </item>
</group>
<group title="Virtual panel">
<item type="-"> Several errors with incorrect positioning of the cursor on the
    FAR panel after operations of renaming and deleting were
    corrected. </item>
<item type="-"> In the Far alpha 6 it wasn't possible to go to the parent catalog
    through ".." </item>
<item type="+"> New type of named folder: now you can specify environment
    variable as path to the named folder in the form of "%var%". </item>
<item type="*"> Character-separator between paths for active and inactive panels 
    in the path of named folders was changed from "\n" to "|".</item>
</group>
<group title="Misc">
<item type="-"> The plugin was failed after cancellation of the submenu in the 
    plugins menu. </item>
<item type="-"> Help and lang files were corrected. </item>
</group>
</version>

<version product_name="Named Folders" version="2.0 beta 1" date="26.01.2004">
<group title="General">
<item type="+"> Catalogs are supported now. </item>
<item type="*"> Filters were removed.  </item>
<item type="*"> If a shortcut to a non-existing folder is selected, the plugin will suggest
    to go to the nearest existing folder in the shortcut path. </item>
<item type="!"> Now the site of this plugin are http://www.rammus.ru  </item>
</group>
<group title="Virtual panel">
<item type="*"> F7 is opened the dialog for creation catalog. </item>
<item type="+"> The copping any directory to the virtual panel of the plugin
    will lead to the implicit creation of the shortcut. </item>
<item type="+"> It's possible to copy and remove catalogs and shortcuts through F5 and F6.</item>  
<item type="-"> Now previous view mode of the virtual panel is restored automatically. </item>
</group>
<group title="Command line">
<item type="+"> Now it's possible to use metasymbols * and ? in the names of shortcuts,
	catalogs and paths.</item>
<item type="!"> Now in the commands of opening and deleting the names of shortcut 
	in the general case writing as [catalog/][shortcut][\path related named folder].</item>
<item type="+"> New commands to create shortcut for two folders.
    Commands "cd:::shortcut" and "cd::+shortcut" will create, accordingly,
	constant and temporary shortcut for two folders, opened on 
	active and inactive panels.</item>
<item type="+"> New commands for implicit creation of shortcuts: "cd::", "cd:+",
    "cd:::", "cd::+". As the name of shortcut the name of the opened
	directory will be used. </item>
<item type="-"> New command for implicit deletion of the shortcut: "cd:-".
	This command display menu with the list of shortcuts for 
	currently opened and directory and its subdirectories.
	Selected shortcut will be deleted.</item>
<item type="+"> New command for finding shortcut by the text included in the 
	path of named folder: "cd:~mask". </item>
<item type="+"> Now it's possible to execute any command through
	"Command execution dialog" (F11 -> Named Folders 2.0 -> Execute command). 
	In contrast to command line, it's possible to skip plugins prefix "cd:"
	in this case. File "ApplyCommand.reg" is allowed to set hot key "Ctrl+D"
	for this dialog. </item>
<item type="*"> Now it's possible to search shortcuts by Alt+F7. </item>
</group> 
<group title="Settings">
<item type="+"> New confirmations for overriding existing shortcut, deleting catalogs 
	and shortcuts, going to the nearest folder, creating and deleting 
	shortcut implicitly.</item>
<item type="+"> New flag "always show all variants" which define the behavior of the
	plugin in the case, when several shortcuts satisfied to specified
	mask but only one of them satisfied exactly. I.e. user 
	type shortcut name "a" and plugin find shortcuts "a" and "ab". 
	If this flag is ON plugin will display menu with both variants,
	otherwise plugin will open shortcut "a". </item>
</group>
<group title="Misc">
<item type="-"> Now the registry key for saving shortcuts are dependent from the user of FAR.
	(Previously the plugin save all data to 
	HKEY_CURRENT_USER\Software\Far\Plugins\NamedFolders)</item>
<item type="*"> Now the plugin has two default prefixes: "cd" and "cc"</item>
</group>
</version>
</whatsnew>