<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>

<whatsnew>
<version product_name="Named Folders" version="4.0.0.284 beta 1" date="29.08.2013"> 
<item type="!">NF 4.X works under FAR 3 only. For FAR 2 please use NF 3.X.</item>
<item type="!">All shortcuts are stored in sqlite now, Windows registry is not used anymore.</item>
<item type="!">Both x86 and x64 versions of NF are used same shortcuts database.</item>
<item type="*">Temporary shortucts work as general shorcuts. I.e. commands cd:+ и cd:: are equal.</item>
<item>If two NF panels are opened at the same time and you change data on one panel, then data on another panel is NOT updated automatically. Custom update is required.</item>
</version>

<version product_name="Named Folders" version="3.0.0.259 snapshot" date="10.04.2011"> 
<item type="+">Now, it's possible to execute known folders directly from command
line using "cd:shell:abc" comman (abc - is known folder name).</item>
<item type="*">From this version command cd: soft executes applications from
separate thread. So, command returns control to FAR immediatelly, without waiting
when finish of application launch. Catalog of the application is also opened in 
separate thread, so this operation doesn't hang FAR anymore.</item>
<item type="+">Set of supported keys in variant menu in command cd: soft was changed.
Now, Ctrl+Alt+Enter is used instead of Shift+Enter for opening application directory
in FAR. There are two new key sequences here. Shift+Enter executes application
without closing menu, Shift+Ctrl+Enter opens application directory in Explorer 
without closing menu.</item>
<item type="-">cs: "word" didn't work without space after ":". </item>
</version>


<version product_name="Named Folders" version="3.0.0.258 snapshot" date="2.04.2011"> 
<item type="+">NF supports Known Folders under Vista/Windows 7.
(see. http://www.sevenforums.com/tutorials/4941-shell-command.html).
There are to variants of using known folders. Firsly, you can create alias
for registy key
$HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\\SOFTWARE\\Microsoft\\Windows\\CurrentVersion\\explorer\\FolderDescriptions
The plugins "knows" this key and is able to read list of registered known
directories from it. Such shortuct "shell" is add to standard file "StdPaths.reg". 
"shell" is replaced depricated "stdu" and "stda" under Vista/Win7.
Secondly, you can set expressions "shell:abc" as shortcut values.
Plugin recognizes command "shell:abc" as request to open known folder with
name matched to "*abc*" (issue #55). </item>
<item type="+">Now it's possible to edit catalog properties using F4.</item>
<item type="+">Support of Windows 7 is implemented. Two new command parameters
are introduced: "+lib" and "-lib". You can use it in such way:
1) cd::abc +lib - create shortcut abc for current directory + add current directory
to exist win7-library.
2) cd:-abc -lib - remove shortcut abc and remove its directory from win7-libraries.
3) cd: +lib - add current directory to exist win7-library.
4) cd: -lib - remove current directory from win7-libraries.
NF always suggest to select required Win7-library from list of exist libraries.
Plugin uses libraries that are registered in Windows Explorer.
</item>
<item type="+">New flag in catalog properties: 
"Ask to add to default Win7 library automatically". If this flag turned on,
then if you add new shortcut to catalog then plugin will suggest to add
directory for this plugin to Win7-library even if "-lib" wasn't used.. And
in opposite, if you remove shortcut from library, the plugin will suggest
to remove it from win7-libraries even if "-lib" wasn't used.
</item>
<item type="+">New catalog property "Default Win7-library". This is library
that should be shown first in the list of libraries when plugin suggest to user
to select win7-library.
</item>
<item type="+">Pattern "cs: abc" allows to specify name abc in quotes and use
spaces in abc, i.e. cs: "a b c"</item>
<item type="+">New prefix "st:" to launch application through NF. This is first
step for #29. Now, it's possible to launch applications in such way: "st:soft". 
Modificators ":" and "+" (i.e. "cd: :soft" and "cd: +soft") are NOT supported yet,
we need different syntax here. Important: plugins registers two prefixes by
default: "cd:" and "st:". If you install the plugin over previos versions,
new prefix "st:" won't be added automatically, you need to specify it 
manually in settings.</item>
<item type="+">New catalog attribute: "show in disk menu". If this flag
is turned on AND flag "allow to show in disk menu" is turned on in plugin
settings, then plugin will show this catalog in disk menu.</item>
<item type="+">Flag "Show catalogs in disk menu" in the plugin configuration
dialog is replaced by "Allow to show catalogs in disk menu" (issue #8).</item>
</version>

<version product_name="Named Folders" version="3.0.0.256 snapshot" date="12.02.2011"> 
<item type="+">New possibility to specify negative mask in paths. Negative mask is
separated from positive one by character "|". I.e. command "cd:pf\*a*|*b*" will 
find all subdirectories of "pf" that are matched to "*a*" and, at the same time,
not matched to "*b*".</item>
<item type="+">New modificator for application launch command:
"cd: +soft" automatically copies path to currently active file to clipboard, 
issue #52.</item>
<item type="+">Command "cd: soft" allows to use quotes, i.e. 'cd: "soft"'.
"Soft" can contain spaces. Spaces work as logical OR, i.e. command 'cd: "a b c"' 
shows applications which names match to "a" OR "b" OR" "c", issue #52</item>
<item type="-">Не работали ярлыки, ссылающиеся ни на директории, а на файлы.
Issue #49</item>
<item type="-">Fixed issue #53 - there was a problem with jumping to root
folder from subdirectory using command "cd:.\..\".</item>
<item type="-">Mode "shotrcuts-values" in shorctucts variant menu didn't work.</item>
<item type="*">Distance between columns in variants menu are made equal 2 spaces
instead of 1 space.</item>
<item type="-">Columns in variants menu were formatted incorrectly if item
names were very long, issue #54</item>
<item type="+">New view mode in variants menu for command "cd: soft": 
"application-directory", issue #54</item>
<item type="*">View modes in variants menu are changed by F5-F9. 
Keys F1-F4 are reserved for other possible commands.</item>
<item type="+">New possibility to sort results by selected column in variants
menu. Use Ctrl+F5, Ctrl+F6 and Ctrl+F7 to select 1,2,3 columns, Ctrl+F12 -
to display results unsorted. Selected column are displayed in variant menu
in round brackets.</item>
<item type="*">Performance of filter in variants menu is significantly improved.</item>
<item type="+">New possibility to select NF in FAR dialogs. Open dialog, set cursor
to edit box, enter command (with or without prefix "cd:"), press F11 and select
Named Folders in the opened list of plugins. NF executes the command and returns
result directory to the edit box. All "open" commands are supported beside "cd: soft". 
All commands for creation and deletion are ignored.</item>
</version>

<version product_name="Named Folders" version="3.0.0.254 release" date="22.01.2011"> 
<item type="*">Minor code improvements.</item>
<item type="*">Help is improved.</item>
</version>

<version product_name="Named Folders" version="3.0.0.253 RC2" date="16.01.2011"> 
<item type="!">Plugin supports two new  metacharacters "\**:N" and "\..*:N".
They allow to limit deep search for search in deep and search up.
Metacharacters "\**" and "\..*" are used for search with unlimited level search.
If option "Short syntax in paths" is turned on, then you are able to use
alternative variant for these metacharactes: N slashes and N+1 dots.</item>
<item type="-">Command "cd:\\network_path" to open network paths directly 
doesn't work in previous versions of the plugin. Now it's implemented.</item>
<item type="-">Pressing Esc during process of searching stopped search process
without visualisation of already found results.</item>
<item type="-">Plugin don't open aliases that links network directories with
dot(s) in path, i.e. "\\computer\abc.cde"</item>
<item type="-">Commands "cd:%var%" and "cd:%var" don't work under WinXP in 
some cases.</item>
<item type="+">Command "cd:path" allows to specify path in quotes, i.e. 
cd:"c:\temp"</item>
<item type="+">Commands cd:--f" and "cd:--df" supports new possibility to
specify required directory directly, without alias. I.e. "cd:--f c:\temp\**". 
If required path contains spaces, the path should be qouted, i.e.:
cd:--df "c:\program files\**:2\*diz"</item>
<item type="*">Help is improved</item>
</version>

<version product_name="Named Folders" version="3.0.0.249 RC1" date="7.01.2011"> 
<item type="*">Direct path commands use technology of search by related
paths (see above). I.e. they support metachars "\**", "..*", "\*", "\..".
Commands "cd:z:" and "cd:z:\" are executed as "cd:z:\*"</item>
<item type="-">Command "cd:a/" created catalog. Now, it doesn't create
catalog but only open exist catalog on NF-panel, see #38</item>
<item type="+">Implicit commands of creation shortcuts for two directories
(on both panels) are implemented: "cd:::", "cd::+", "cd:::catalog/",
"cd::+catalog/", see #38</item>
<item type="-">Command "cd::a/" didn't create catalog "a" if name of
catalog contained only single letter, see #38</item>
<item type="-">Pressing Ctrl+'/' on NF-panel resulted to creation garbage
catalogs on panel, see #39. Now, Ctrl+'/' opens parent directory and set
position on "..". Ctrl+PageUp opens parent directory and set position on
previously selected catalog, see #41.</item>
<item type="-">Implicit shorcut creation commands allow to specify catalog,
i.e: cd::catalog1/. If "catalog1" doesn't exists the command will suggest
to create catalog, not shorcut. So, to create shortcut with implicit name
in new catalog "catalog1" you should execute command "cd::catalog1/" two
times.</item>
<item type="*">Command cd::a/b suggests to create "a", if "a" doesn't
exist, and the suggests to create shortcut "b". Previously it did nothing
if "a" didn't exist. See #20.</item>
<item type="-">A lot of bugs were fixed.</item>
</version>

<version product_name="Named Folders" version="3.0.0.245 beta" date="25.12.2010"> 
<group title="Key changes">
<item type="!">Plugin uses Far API 2.0 and unicode.</item>	
<item type="!">64-bit version of the plugin is released. Now plugin is available both for x86 and x64.</item>	
<item type="!">Plugin has own open source project on google code: 
http://code.google.com/p/namedfolders/. You can write bugreports and suggestion to
issue tracker here. You can also download most recent snapshot of the plugin
(all releases will be send to PlugRing as previously).</item>	
<item type="!">NF3 doesn't work correctly with russian shortcuts, that
were created under NF2. As result, it's necessary to recreate all shortcuts,
that contain Russian letters in names and/or in paths.</item>
</group>
<group title="Changes">
<item type="-">Launch of x64-apps from FAR x86 is fixed, see #6 
(http://code.google.com/p/namedfolders/issues/detail?id=6)</item>	
<item type="*">Procedure of removing douple prefixes is changed. In previous
versions NF, command "cD:ab:command" was equal to "cd:command" and  
command "cd:cd:cd:command" didn't work at all. Now, the plugin ignores
all prefixes except last one. So, the command "ab:cd:ef:command" is
equal to "ef:command".</item>
<item type="*">Search in local paths is changed. No, the command "cd:alias.." 
can be written in more classic way "cd:alias\..". Both variants ".." and "\.."
are supported to specify parent folder.</item>
<item type="+">New possibility to edit shortuct from variants menu.
F4 is used to edit menu. To change view mode "shorctuts and values" on
plese use F7 instead of F4.</item>
<item type="+">Macros FastPrefix is fixed for Far 2.0. Now, key ':'
types "cd:" in command line and changes Russian to English if Russian
layout was selected. So, you can press ':' and types your NF command
in English langugage.</item>
<item type="+">Variants menu shows total list of items.</item>
<item type="!">Technology of search by related paths is completely changed.
New metacharacters "\**" and "\..*" are used to search without deep
limitations insted of depricatead metacharacters "\*\" and "\.\".
Sequence of N-metacharacters "\*", "\.." is used to search on 
N levels instead of sequence of slashes and dishes. Old syntax
with slashes and dishes are supported also (it can be turned on/off
in plugin settings, see param "Short syntax in paths".
See wiki page 
http://code.google.com/p/namedfolders/wiki/WIkiRelatedPathsRu 
for details.
</item>
<item type="*">If you execute command "cd:a\path" and plugin hasn't found
directory matched to "path", it will show standard confirmation 
"do you want to go to nearest directory?". Previous version didn't
show confirmation, they open the directory assigned to shortcut "a".
You can disable this confirmations in plugin settings.</item>
</group>

<group title="Settings">
<item type="*">Possibility to specify fast key for the plugin in disk
menu is removed. It's not actual anymore after releasing Far 2.0 build
1692. Issue #15</item>
<item type="+">New flag "Show catalogs in disk menu". If it's turned on,
then NF shows catalog in disk menu besid standard menu item "Named Folders".
This is experimental implementation of Issue #8.</item>
<item type="+">New flag "Short syntax in paths". This flag enables
possibility to use "\\\" instead of "\*\*\*" and "...." instead of "\..\.."
in related path. Also, it allows to use "cd:a.." instead of "cd:a\.."
</item>
</group>
</version>

</whatsnew>